

Reeta khadka

Email: reetikakhadka74@gmail.com

Computer Engineer with 5+ years of experience as Broadcast Engineering and SMS system of DTH.Familiar with Subscriber Management System software and conflict resolution and possesses a positive attitude. Knowledge of Artificial Intelligence, Machine learning and Deep learning. Sound knowledge of Cloud Computing and Amazon Web Service. Seeking a career change to a position Project Management. Fast learner who has volunteered in **Women in Big Data Chapter Nepal**.Certified **Register Scrum Master**.

CONTACT INFO

Name: Reeta khadka

Phone: 9841506739

Address: Kathmandu, Sadobato

WORK EXPERIENCE

March 2022 - Present

Job Title: Trainee Scrum Master Organisation: Codavatar Tech Pvt Ltd

Responsibilities:

- Host daily stand-up meetings.
- Ensure Agile Engineering Practices.
- Arrange and optimize product backlog.
- Organize scrum events as necessary.
- Sprint Planning and Story Point Estimations .
- Capacity and velocity Estimation

May 2020 - Present

Job Title: Operation Team Leader

Organisation: Women in Big Data Nepal

Responsibilities

- Facilitate coordination and communication between teams to support functions of the organisation to meet programme objectives.
- Responsible for the retention and growth of the chapter's community through an improved operation process.
- Provide timely status, variance and monitoring reports to the Board about the ongoing operations .
- Strengthen and support collaborative learning and team building activities.
- Planned and organised data literacy programs through various internal sessions.

Dec 2016 - Dec 2017

Job Title: Senior Technical Engineer

Organisation: Nepal Digital Cable Pvt.Ltd (Hamro TV)

Responsibilities

- Rapidly identify and correct system faults to minimise operational downtime of broadcast.
- Performed scheduled service work, including testing and repairs and worked to strengthen the signal quality during broadcast.
- Worked on Planning and assisting for the design and development of SMS systems.
- Testing Software of Set-top Box, for best suitable software for DTH.

May 2014 - October 2016

Job Title: Broadcast Engineer

Organization: Dish Media Network Pvt.Ltd

Responsibilities

- Monitoring satellite tracking, transmission and broadcasting system with proper log sheet database preparation.
- Identify signal parameters and troubleshoot issues using test equipment including waveform monitors, and audio distortion analyzers
- Performed an Emergency fixing as stopgap until maintenance teams could conduct advanced repairs.
- Management of Head-end-units through proper operational checkup and prepare datasets. , worked to strengthen the audio and video quality during broadcast.
- Monitor the Operation of the Master Control Room (MCR).
- Schedule and ingest of Program Guide.(*electronic program guide*) of the channel.
- Assisting technicians and CSR for the system troubleshoot and equipment installation.

March 2011-April 2014

Job Title: SMS and CAS Engineer

Organization: Dish Media Network Pvt.Ltd

Responsibilities

- Worked in collaboration with the R&D team on the hardware failure of Set-up-box and testing Software of Set-top Box after update.
- Reporting and Analyzing the Activation and Deactivation Status of the Set-up-box.
- Handled the billing issue of the Set-up-box.
- Periodic reconciliation system features.
- Assisting the CSR team and helping them with technical issue arrived in the SMS system.
- Reporting inventory details of Set-up- box to the board.
- Assisted and Lead the team of 20 employees for the audit during the migration of system data.
- Assisted the dealer and sub-dealer to use the SMS(Subscriber Management System) and its features.

EDUCATION

2017-2020: Master of Computer Engineering

CERTIFICATES

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Registered Scrum Master

PROJECTS

Headline generation from Nepali News using LSTM Neural Network

Web info Search Engine

Health Management System

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming language:Python,C,C++
- Database: Oracle 10g
- Broadcast Engineer, Transmission, Inventory controls
- SMS system
- AWS(Amazon Web Service)
- Project Management /Agile/Scrum

SOFT SKILLS

- Team work
- Team lead
- Research

- Problem solving
- Descision making
- Presentation

LANGUAGE

- Nepali
- English
- Hindi